import { NoteContent } from '../note-seed.service';

export const geographyContents: NoteContent[] = [
  {
    question: 'Столица Франции',
    answer: 'Париж',
    tags: ['география', 'столицы', 'Европа'],
  },
  {
    question: 'Столица Японии',
    answer: 'Токио',
    tags: ['география', 'столицы', 'Азия'],
  },
  {
    question: 'Столица Австралии',
    answer: 'Канберра',
    tags: ['география', 'столицы', 'Океания'],
  },
  {
    question: 'Столица США',
    answer: 'Вашингтон',
    tags: ['география', 'столицы', 'Северная Америка'],
  },
  {
    question: 'Столица Великобритании',
    answer: 'Лондон',
    tags: ['география', 'столицы', 'Европа'],
  },
  {
    question: 'Столица Германии',
    answer: 'Берлин',
    tags: ['география', 'столицы', 'Европа'],
  },
  {
    question: 'Столица Италии',
    answer: 'Рим',
    tags: ['география', 'столицы', 'Европа'],
  },
  {
    question: 'Столица Испании',
    answer: 'Мадрид',
    tags: ['география', 'столицы', 'Европа'],
  },
  {
    question: 'Столица Китая',
    answer: 'Пекин',
    tags: ['география', 'столицы', 'Азия'],
  },
  {
    question: 'Столица Индии',
    answer: 'Нью-Дели',
    tags: ['география', 'столицы', 'Азия'],
  },
  {
    question: 'Столица Бразилии',
    answer: 'Бразилиа',
    tags: ['география', 'столицы', 'Южная Америка'],
  },
  {
    question: 'Столица Канады',
    answer: 'Оттава',
    tags: ['география', 'столицы', 'Северная Америка'],
  },
  {
    question: 'Столица Мексики',
    answer: 'Мехико',
    tags: ['география', 'столицы', 'Северная Америка'],
  },
  {
    question: 'Столица России',
    answer: 'Москва',
    tags: ['география', 'столицы', 'Европа/Азия'],
  },
  {
    question: 'Столица Южной Кореи',
    answer: 'Сеул',
    tags: ['география', 'столицы', 'Азия'],
  },
  {
    question: 'Столица Египта',
    answer: 'Каир',
    tags: ['география', 'столицы', 'Африка'],
  },
  {
    question: 'Столица Турции',
    answer: 'Анкара',
    tags: ['география', 'столицы', 'Азия/Европа'],
  },
  {
    question: 'Столица ЮАР',
    answer:
      'Претория (административная), Кейптаун (законодательная), Блумфонтейн (судебная)',
    tags: ['география', 'столицы', 'Африка'],
  },
  {
    question: 'Столица Аргентины',
    answer: 'Буэнос-Айрес',
    tags: ['география', 'столицы', 'Южная Америка'],
  },
  {
    question: 'Столица Нидерландов',
    answer: 'Амстердам',
    tags: ['география', 'столицы', 'Европа'],
  },
  {
    question: 'Столица Швеции',
    answer: 'Стокгольм',
    tags: ['география', 'столицы', 'Европа'],
  },
  {
    question: 'Столица Норвегии',
    answer: 'Осло',
    tags: ['география', 'столицы', 'Европа'],
  },
  {
    question: 'Столица Дании',
    answer: 'Копенгаген',
    tags: ['география', 'столицы', 'Европа'],
  },
  {
    question: 'Столица Финляндии',
    answer: 'Хельсинки',
    tags: ['география', 'столицы', 'Европа'],
  },
  {
    question: 'Столица Греции',
    answer: 'Афины',
    tags: ['география', 'столицы', 'Европа'],
  },
  {
    question: 'Столица Португалии',
    answer: 'Лиссабон',
    tags: ['география', 'столицы', 'Европа'],
  },
  {
    question: 'Столица Австрии',
    answer: 'Вена',
    tags: ['география', 'столицы', 'Европа'],
  },
  {
    question: 'Столица Швейцарии',
    answer: 'Берн',
    tags: ['география', 'столицы', 'Европа'],
  },
  {
    question: 'Столица Бельгии',
    answer: 'Брюссель',
    tags: ['география', 'столицы', 'Европа'],
  },
  {
    question: 'Столица Польши',
    answer: 'Варшава',
    tags: ['география', 'столицы', 'Европа'],
  },
  {
    question: 'Столица Чехии',
    answer: 'Прага',
    tags: ['география', 'столицы', 'Европа'],
  },
  {
    question: 'Столица Венгрии',
    answer: 'Будапешт',
    tags: ['география', 'столицы', 'Европа'],
  },
  {
    question: 'Столица Румынии',
    answer: 'Бухарест',
    tags: ['география', 'столицы', 'Европа'],
  },
  {
    question: 'Столица Болгарии',
    answer: 'София',
    tags: ['география', 'столицы', 'Европа'],
  },
  {
    question: 'Столица Украины',
    answer: 'Киев',
    tags: ['география', 'столицы', 'Европа'],
  },
  {
    question: 'Столица Беларуси',
    answer: 'Минск',
    tags: ['география', 'столицы', 'Европа'],
  },
  {
    question: 'Столица Казахстана',
    answer: 'Астана',
    tags: ['география', 'столицы', 'Азия'],
  },
  {
    question: 'Столица Узбекистана',
    answer: 'Ташкент',
    tags: ['география', 'столицы', 'Азия'],
  },
  {
    question: 'Столица Новой Зеландии',
    answer: 'Веллингтон',
    tags: ['география', 'столицы', 'Океания'],
  },
  {
    question: 'Столица Израиля',
    answer: 'Иерусалим (оспаривается)',
    tags: ['география', 'столицы', 'Азия'],
  },
  {
    question: 'Столица Ирана',
    answer: 'Тегеран',
    tags: ['география', 'столицы', 'Азия'],
  },
  {
    question: 'Столица Саудовской Аравии',
    answer: 'Эр-Рияд',
    tags: ['география', 'столицы', 'Азия'],
  },
  {
    question: 'Столица ОАЭ',
    answer: 'Абу-Даби',
    tags: ['география', 'столицы', 'Азия'],
  },
  {
    question: 'Столица Марокко',
    answer: 'Рабат',
    tags: ['география', 'столицы', 'Африка'],
  },
  {
    question: 'Столица Алжира',
    answer: 'Алжир',
    tags: ['география', 'столицы', 'Африка'],
  },
  {
    question: 'Столица Нигерии',
    answer: 'Абуджа',
    tags: ['география', 'столицы', 'Африка'],
  },
  {
    question: 'Столица Кении',
    answer: 'Найроби',
    tags: ['география', 'столицы', 'Африка'],
  },
  {
    question: 'Столица Перу',
    answer: 'Лима',
    tags: ['география', 'столицы', 'Южная Америка'],
  },
  {
    question: 'Столица Колумбии',
    answer: 'Богота',
    tags: ['география', 'столицы', 'Южная Америка'],
  },
  {
    question: 'Столица Чили',
    answer: 'Сантьяго',
    tags: ['география', 'столицы', 'Южная Америка'],
  },
  {
    question: 'Столица Вьетнама',
    answer: 'Ханой',
    tags: ['география', 'столицы', 'Азия'],
  },
  {
    question: 'Столица Таиланда',
    answer: 'Бангкок',
    tags: ['география', 'столицы', 'Азия'],
  },
  {
    question: 'Столица Малайзии',
    answer: 'Куала-Лумпур',
    tags: ['география', 'столицы', 'Азия'],
  },
  {
    question: 'Столица Индонезии',
    answer: 'Джакарта',
    tags: ['география', 'столицы', 'Азия'],
  },
  {
    question: 'Столица Филиппин',
    answer: 'Манила',
    tags: ['география', 'столицы', 'Азия'],
  },
  {
    question: 'Столица Сингапура',
    answer: 'Сингапур',
    tags: ['география', 'столицы', 'Азия'],
  },
  {
    question: 'Столица Ирландии',
    answer: 'Дублин',
    tags: ['география', 'столицы', 'Европа'],
  },
  {
    question: 'Столица Исландии',
    answer: 'Рейкьявик',
    tags: ['география', 'столицы', 'Европа'],
  },
  {
    question: 'Столица Кубы',
    answer: 'Гавана',
    tags: ['география', 'столицы', 'Северная Америка'],
  },
  {
    question: 'Столица Ямайки',
    answer: 'Кингстон',
    tags: ['география', 'столицы', 'Северная Америка'],
  },
];
